<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
	<name>Fantasy Goblins Updated</name>
	<author>Vagabond, Barsimmon</author>
	<url>https://github.com/Barsimmon/FantasyGoblinsUpdated</url>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.1</li>
		<li>1.2</li>
		<li>1.3</li>
		<li>1.4</li>
		<li>1.5</li>
	</supportedVersions>
	<packageId>Barsimmon.OriginalByVagabond.FantasyGoblins</packageId>
	<modDependencies>
		<li>
			<packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
			<displayName>Harmony</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
			<downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
		</li>
	</modDependencies>
	<loadAfter>
		<li>erdelf.HumanoidAlienRaces</li>
		<li>erdelf.HumanoidAlienRaces.dev</li>
		<li>brrainz.harmony</li>
	</loadAfter>
	<!--<loadBefore>
    <li>CETeam.CombatExtended</li>
	</loadBefore>-->
	<description>
Goblins! Xenotype/race, faction, scenario, items, buildings, tech, ...
This mod requires either Biotech or Humanoid Alien Races. See this dependency grid for details:

[img]https://i.imgur.com/yAUa2Yh.png[/img]

This mod was first made by Vagabond, I just updated it with retroactive permission.
I did not make any of the original art, but the goblin textures have been edited for compatibility with vanilla clothes and expansion features.
I also didn't come up with this concept. I just fixed bugs, nerfed the goblins, and updated for compatibility with Rimworld versions and expansions.

Original mod: https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1465072243

Let me know if you find any bugs. Suggestions also welcome.

If anyone wants to help, I've got some to-do's at the bottom. If you find a fix or want to contribute in another way, tell me about it via Steam, or make a pull request on Github:

https://github.com/Barsimmon/FantasyGoblinsUpdated

Translations
----------------
Japanese by Lucifel: https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2568016898
Chinese by waghhhhhhhhhhhh: https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2584854456

Patches
----------------
Partial CE patch by Gorlath: https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2792708861

Original description below
--------------------------

Adds the race of sly and conniving goblins. While physically weak they
more than make up for it with their productivity and intellectual cunning.

Goblins are focused mainly on a tribal playthrough.


FEATURES
--------

Goblins as a playable race.

Goblins are physically weaker with decreased hit points.
They're however faster and have higher rate's of resistance
towards diseases and toxicity.

Hostile and friendly goblin settlements.

Mud gathering. Mud is a resource that can be harvested from mud pits.
Mud can then be used in the construction of weak mud walls.
While not being able to suffer much physical abuse they're highly fire-resistant.

New Walls.
- Mud walls.
- Wooden palisade.
- Goblin made stone walls.

New Floor Tiles.
- A crude makeshift wooden plank tile.
- Mud floor.
- Goblin made flagstone.

New Weapons.
- An array of neolithic and medieval weapons to equip your
goblin tribe with.

- A few late game guns, if your tribe survives long enough to get out of the
dark ages.

New Armour.
- Equip your goblins in the latest of tribal fashion.
Such as tribal masks, simple leather armours, and warlord armour
for your chieftains.
Warlord armour can only be used by goblins.

New Furniture
- Added more suitable furniture for your goblin tribe.
Such as crude wooden planked tables, stools.
And a variety of decoration and lighting options as well as a
few more things
that I'll hope you'll enjoy in your playthrough.

New Backstories
- I've currently disabled all goblin backstories
for now.
Sorry if this causes any immersion breaking inconveniences.
They currently use the vanilla tribal backstories.



Have fun.



Barsimmon's changes
---------------------
- Updated for 1.1
- Get rid of Defs that override vanilla Defs
- Non-goblins should no longer spawn with goblin apparel
- Added quiver, berserker armor and warlord armor for Fat, Hulk, Thin and Female body types to fix missing texture bug
- Moonshade soup recipe now exists
- Split up male and female body types so females have correct apparel textures
- Added backstories based on and copied from tribal backstories
- Gave goblins some plastic surgery so vanilla apparel fits their bodies
- Moonshade inkcap now dies in sunlight so should be grown in the dark
- Don't use cover art with female goblin that doen't exist in the mod
- Mud production now uses food making sounds instead of stone cutting sounds
- Mud floor no longer flammable and doesn't turn into burned wooden
- Mud floor now has beauty of -1
- Naming errors shouldn't occur as often
- Wrestling pit, gibbet and banner icons are smaller in build menu
- Goblin stuff is locked behind techs. Neolithic techs are granted to the goblin tribal start
- Nerfed plumbata. Is now more like pila instead of like a shotgun
- Nerfed axes
- Fixed the squirrel meat bug by renaming def Mud_Pit to Goblin_Mud_Pit. Added dll that fixes saves from before this fix (2020-04-03)
- Added custom JobDriver for wrestling pit. Wrestling pit is now actually 3x3, pawns are now actually standing in it and the sounds are no longer the same as playing billiards
- Patch GenConstruct and GenSpawn to fix goblin wall behaviour so canPlaceOverWall works
- Updated to 1.2
- Updated some syntax for Humanoid Alien Races
- Removed references to thoughts and traits that no longer exist in the base game
- Nerf race stats, armor stats, quiver stats
- Give Goblins the nature meditation focus
- Remove references to base tribal faction and pawnkind to improve compatibility
- Add goblin nicknames to prevent naming errors
- Added improved mud and stone floor textures, provided by Delta1138
- Updated to 1.3
- Basic Ideology integration
- Removed Harmony patch for saves older than 2020-04-03 (squirrel meat bug) as I don't think anyone is dragging around a save from 1.1 anymore. Still works if you're not yet on 1.3
- Removed Harmony patch used to make sure doors can be placed over goblin walls in favor of new(?) xml solution.
- Change goblin starting gear
- Fix red errors when loading mod without Ideology
- Fixed mud table, so it's an actual table
- Updated to 1.4
- Nerfed goblins some more, now weaker than humans in melee, and only 10% work speed bonus instead of 20%
- Set mod to be incompatible with Biotech
- Remove color from goblin textures so multiple skin colors are possible
- Separate heads and ears, so more combinations are possible
- Support 1.4 head types
- Added goblin body, head, ears, skin color and hair genes
- Make sure vanilla cosmetic genes that clash with the goblin art are not rendered
- Added goblin and hobgoblin xenotypes
- Patch out Humanoid Alien Races xml if Biotech is present
- Set mod to be compatible with Biotech
- Fix save compatibility
- Add alpha masks for goblin heads so the eyes can be yellow again
- Buff armors somewhat
- Update for 1.5 (XML syntax and rewrite Harmony patches for new pawn rendering system)
- Fix scenario so you don't have to click twice after selecting pawns
- Fix HAR compatibility

Todo's
------
- gibbet should be able to contain prisoners, is just decorative right now.
- rotate gibbet
- sleeping/poison blowdart
- nets
- poison trap
- alpha levels for armour
- better goblin warlord armour for fat and female body types
- change map icons
- Use 1.1 quest system in some way
- Use 1.1 rank system in some way
- make floors less repetitive
- mud wall shows dirt between wall and floor
- No Goblins sold by slave traders
- Improve texture quality
- armor alpha masks
- More medieval/modern armors and accessories (gloves/gauntlets, boots, cloaks)
- More firearms



	</description>
</ModMetaData>
