<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
	<name>Fantasy Goblins Forked</name>
	<author>Vagabond, Barsimmon</author>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.1</li>
	</supportedVersions>
	<packageId>Barsimmon.OriginalByVagabond.FantasyGoblins</packageId>
	<modDependencies>
		<li>
      <packageId>erdelf.HumanoidAlienRaces</packageId>
      <displayName>Humanoid Alien Races 2.0</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/839005762</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
	</modDependencies>
	<loadAfter>
		<li>erdelf.HumanoidAlienRaces</li>
	</loadAfter>
	<description>
		This mod by Vagabond was last updated in 2018 and seemed abandoned.
		I like the mod a lot so I took it upon myself to update it.
		I did not make any of the art, or did any of the creative thinking.
		If Vagabond asks me to take this down, I will.

		Original description below
		--------------------------

		Adds the race of sly and conniving goblins. While physically weak they
		more than make up for it with their productivity and intellectual cunning.

		Goblins are focused mainly on a tribal playthrough.


		REQUIRES

		Version 1.0 of the Humanoid Alien Races mod. Made by Erdelf.

		FEATURES
		--------

		Goblins as a playable race.

		Goblins are physically weaker with decreased hit points.
		They're however faster and have higher rate's of resistance
		towards diseases and toxcicity.

		Hostile and friendly goblin settlements.

		Mud gathering. Mud is a resource that can be harvested from mud pits.
		Mud can then be used in the construction of weak mud walls.
		While not being
		able to suffer much physical abuse they're highly fire resistant.

		New Walls.
		- Mud walls.
		- Wooden palisade.
		- Goblin made stone walls.

		New Floor Tiles.
		- A crude makeshift wooden plank tile.
		- Mud floor.
		- Goblin made flagstone.

		New Weapons.
		- An array of neolithic and medieval weapons to equip your
		goblin tribe with.

		- A few late game guns, if your tribe survives long enough to get out of the
		dark ages.

		New Armour.
		- Equip your goblins in the latest of tribal fashion.
		Such as tribal masks, simple leather armours, and warlord armour
		for your chieftains.
		Warlord armour can only be used by goblins.

		New Furniture
		- Added more suitable furniture for your goblin tribe.
		Such as crude wooden planked tables, stools.
		And a variety of decoration and lighting options as well as a
		few more things
		that I'll hope you'll enjoy in your playthrough.


		New Backstories
		- I've currently disabled all goblin backstories
		for now.
		Sorry if this causes any immersion breaking inconveniences.
		They currently use the vanilla tribal backstories.



		Have fun.




	</description>
</ModMetaData>
